BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nahuel Brandán

Contact@nahuelbrandan.com | In linkedin.com/in/nahuelbrandan | Q github.com/nahuelbrandan | Q Cba / Arg

ABOUT ME -

With over 5 years of experience in software development, I specialize in Python and have worked in both the web and aerospace industries. I collaborate efficiently in multidisciplinary teams, implement best development practices, and enhance technical documentation to ensure project reliability and scalability.

I hold a Computer Analyst degree and am committed to continuous learning and impactful problem-solving.

EXPERIENCE

Real Trends 05/2023 - Present

Backend Software Developer

Remote

- Integration with external APIs such as MercadoLibre and Firebase for bug resolution and new functionalities, collaborating closely with multiple areas, maintaining an assertive communication
- Develop software based on Python, Django, Docker, and Celery, among other technologies

Satellogic 06/2022 - 09/2022

Backend Software Developer

Remote

- Refactored an application into two separate entities, reducing coupling and improving maintainability
- · Contributed to improve code quality through regular code reviews and technical discussions

Ascentio | Project: Sabia-Mar

08/2021 - 05/2022

Backend Software Developer

Remote

Satellite mission, with advanced technology for the study of the sea and the ocean.

- · Developed contributions to satellite flight planning and communication modules, using Docker, FastAPI, API
- · Created unit and integration tests, using Robot Framework, Postman, and Pytest
- Documented projects and development processes, using LaTex and Markdown

IncluIT | Project: Junar

03/2019 - 07/2021

Backend Software Developer

Cba - Arg

- Developed and maintained the backend base code of the system, based on Python, Django, and DRF
- Integrated Auth0 and Keycloak technologies as security layers in API management
- Upgraded Django versions and other +15 dependencies, to reduce the technical debt
- Optimized 30% performance in the APIs response time, through cache management and refactors
- Managed technical onboarding to +10 new developers, providing guidance and technical support

EDUCATION -

National University of Córdoba - Argentina

10/2018

Computer Analyst, equivalent to B.S in Computer Science (Graduated)

Cba - Arg

Career with strong emphasis on programming, analysis, and design of systems, databases, and computer networks, combining a solid theoretical understanding with practical skills.

COURSES -

Platzi 01/2021 - 11/2023

Complete more than 100 courses and in constant learning in the professional online academy called Platzi, on topics such as: soft skills, English, Python, tools, and software development.

SKILLS -

- Programming languages: Python, C
- · Databases: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch
- Frameworks: Diango, Diango REST Framework, FastAPI, Robot Framework
- Dev tools: Linux, REST API, Git, GitHub, Bash, Postman, Docker, Celery, Cache
- Languages: **English** (B2 intermediate), **Spanish** (Native)

*